mofa.gov.bd 2016-11-24

# Privacy Policy | Welcome to MOFA Website

**Privacy Policy**

Government of Bangladesh in general and The Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Dhaka (the custodian of this website) in particular respects your privacy and is committed to protect your personal information that you share with us. Generally, you can browse through our website without giving us any information about yourself. We do not collect any information about you unless you choose to provide that information. We may share necessary data with other Government agencies and departments. However, information collected by us is used only for official purposes, internal reviews, improvement of the content of our website, customization of the content and layout of our website and to contact users. We do not use, share or pass on your information for commercial purposes. All record keepers face the possibility of disclosure of their records in some civil, criminal, or administrative matter. Government of Bangladesh could be required to disclose personal information in response to valid legal processes such as a search warrant, or court order. Disclosures may also be necessary to protect the Government's legal rights or during emergencies if physical safety is believed to be at risk.

**What Information about Users does the Ministry of Foreign Affairs collect?**

We consider any information that could reasonably be used to identify you as "personally identifying information." The Ministry of Foreign Affairs does not retain personal identifiable information about you when you visit our website unless you choose to provide such information to us (i.e. sending an e-mail, participating in a survey, responding to a feedback or "contact", etc.). Government departments, agencies and organizations may request personally identifiable information from you in order to provide requested services however, such information is handled as in the case of an in-person visit to that same department, agency or organization.   

**Privacy Policy**

Government of Bangladesh in general and The Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Dhaka (the custodian of this website) in particular respects your privacy and is committed to protect your personal information that you share with us. Generally, you can browse through our website without giving us any information about yourself. We do not collect any information about you unless you choose to provide that information. We may share necessary data with other Government agencies and departments. However, information collected by us is used only for official purposes, internal reviews, improvement of the content of our website, customization of the content and layout of our website and to contact users. We do not use, share or pass on your information for commercial purposes. All record keepers face the possibility of disclosure of their records in some civil, criminal, or administrative matter. Government of Bangladesh could be required to disclose personal information in response to valid legal processes such as a search warrant, or court order. Disclosures may also be necessary to protect the Government's legal rights or during emergencies if physical safety is believed to be at risk.

**What Information about Users does the Ministry of Foreign Affairs collect?**

We consider any information that could reasonably be used to identify you as "personally identifying information." The Ministry of Foreign Affairs does not retain personal identifiable information about you when you visit our website unless you choose to provide such information to us (i.e. sending an e-mail, participating in a survey, responding to a feedback or "contact", etc.). Government departments, agencies and organizations may request personally identifiable information from you in order to provide requested services however, such information is handled as in the case of an in-person visit to that same department, agency or organization.   

**Electronic Communications  **

If you send us an electronic mail message with a question or comment that contains personally identifying information, or fill out a form that e-mails us information, we will use this personally identifying information only to respond to your request. We may redirect your message to another government agency or person who is in a better position to respond to your query or comment. All e-mail messages received contain the e-mail addresses of persons who voluntarily communicated with or requested information from us. Your e-mail addresses are not sold, leased or shared with any non-governmental or commercial entities without your consent. When a user has given us their e-mail address for purposes of communicating with or requesting information from us, that communication becomes part of the public record and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by law. Information submitted via e-mail or web forms may be at risk of being intercepted, read or modified. You are advised not to pass on any personal and confidential information such as security passwords and credit card numbers while using this website unless specifically required by an authorized person. The Ministry of Foreign Affairs in particular or the government of Bangladesh shall not be liable for any misuse or loss of any such information. 

**Cookies  **

A cookie is a small data file that certain web sites write to your hard drive when you visit them. A cookie file can contain information such as a user ID that the site uses to track the pages you've visited, but the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie can't read data off your hard drive or read cookie files created by other sites. At present no parts of this websites use cookies to track user traffic patterns. We may use cookies in future in order to determine the usefulness of our website information to our users and to see how effective our navigational structure is in helping users reach that information.

**Policy Revision and Notification of Changes**

The Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Bangladesh may at any time revise or update this policy without notice. We may inform our users about policy changes through notices on this page containing a version number and date. Any information collected under the current policy will remain subject to these terms. Information collected after any changes take effect will be subject to the revised privacy policy.    

If you send us an electronic mail message with a question or comment that contains personally identifying information, or fill out a form that e-mails us information, we will use this personally identifying information only to respond to your request. We may redirect your message to another government agency or person who is in a better position to respond to your query or comment. All e-mail messages received contain the e-mail addresses of persons who voluntarily communicated with or requested information from us. Your e-mail addresses are not sold, leased or shared with any non-governmental or commercial entities without your consent. When a user has given us their e-mail address for purposes of communicating with or requesting information from us, that communication becomes part of the public record and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by law. Information submitted via e-mail or web forms may be at risk of being intercepted, read or modified. You are advised not to pass on any personal and confidential information such as security passwords and credit card numbers while using this website unless specifically required by an authorized person. The Ministry of Foreign Affairs in particular or the government of Bangladesh shall not be liable for any misuse or loss of any such information. 

**Cookies  **

A cookie is a small data file that certain web sites write to your hard drive when you visit them. A cookie file can contain information such as a user ID that the site uses to track the pages you've visited, but the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie can't read data off your hard drive or read cookie files created by other sites. At present no parts of this websites use cookies to track user traffic patterns. We may use cookies in future in order to determine the usefulness of our website information to our users and to see how effective our navigational structure is in helping users reach that information.

**Policy Revision and Notification of Changes**

The Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Bangladesh may at any time revise or update this policy without notice. We may inform our users about policy changes through notices on this page containing a version number and date. Any information collected under the current policy will remain subject to these terms. Information collected after any changes take effect will be subject to the revised privacy policy.
